## Bhimashankar Jogdand

Mobile No: +91 8237008188 / 8888894642 Email: bhimashankara.j@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have completed **Diploma in Automobile Engineering** – Year 2007

I have attended and successfully completed graduation training program for new project JAGUAR X-760 with the JAGUAR LANDROVER Group of **UK** from **Solihull**.

With Total experience of around 12 years 10 months in the field of Quality Assurance, Vehicle Assembly & Press & BIW Operation Quality.

#### **EDUCATION**

Mumbai MSBTE, Maharashtra Diploma in Automobile Engineering (March 2007)

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

### Executive (L6), Tata Motors Limited, Ahmedabad, Gujrat

June 2019 - Present

- To attend daily morning meeting, share the previous day's problems and its countermeasure taken at respective area.
- NCI is sue tracking (paint shop) and resolution of surface defects.
- Responsible for water leakage action, audit and closure.
- Prepare and Circulate the Daily and Monthly MIS to upper management.
- Responsible for Manpower handling in Various audits in various inspection area regarding the BIW EOL inspection.
- Responsible for time to time training to associates regarding Quality culture.
- Responsible press shop Rejection meeting, rework & decision.
- Responsible for press shop rejection booking.
- Responsible for Tigor & Tiago Tear down activity.
- Responsible for 5F meeting & PSF action closure.
- Responsible for Safety, Kaizen, OPL. 5'S.

## Executive (L6) TATA Jaguar Land Rover Pune Operation, Chikhali, Pune.

March 2011 to May 2019

- Working in new JLR (JAGUAR LANDROVER) project
- Responsible for Water Test, Functional Test and Drive Test.
- Responsible for analysis of problems coming in Drive Test & shower test.
- Root cause analysis of problems occurred during functional inspection.
- Follow-up for continual quality improvements.
- Follow-up for line FTT & FPV.
- Handling daily defects monitoring SIP station (Standard Inspection point) & their analysis for Drive Test & Water Test problems
- Initiate quality improvement plans to improve the quality level of vehicle.
- To update of Work Element Sheet & Quality Process Sheet.
- To monitor & control demerit points of Roll out Audit.
- Co-ordination of daily morning meeting for line problem.
- Updating daily & weekly report for SIP Audit.
- To provide corrective action for Assembly errors.
- Responsible for incoming inspection & rework seat and door pad
- Rejection analysis & reduction of rejection rate by using Quality standards & grey book standard

# Sr. Group Leader (Quality Assurance), Skoda Auto India Pvt. Ltd ,Aurangabad August 2007 to March 2011

- Excellent experience in electrical and functional inspection of vehicles.
- Inspector for final inspection with Quality vehicles of Audit & Pre Delivery Inspection (PDI) with the respective analysis
- Responsible for analysis of problems coming in Drive Test & shower test.
- Root cause analysis of problems occurred during functional inspection.
- Follow-up for continual quality improvements.
- Initiate quality improvement plans to improve the quality level of vehicle

#### **ACTIVITIES & ACHIEVEMENTS**

\_\_\_\_\_

- Major role played in setting work procedures and (WES) Work Element Sheets & Quality Process Sheets for new product launch LANDROVER.
- Skill and Versatility MAN/3QPS QPS/2MAN.
- Increased Direct Pass Rate by using various Quality Visual Documents on several work station.
- Member of Improvement Team and successfully reduced the reworks and rejection.
- Undergone "Special Company Training Unning"

## SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE

- \_\_\_\_\_
- Highly Motivated
- Able to adapt well to a continually changing environment.
- Proficient in use of Microsoft Excel, Word, Outlook Power Point
- Course on Computer Concept (CCC)

## PERSONAL DETAILS

\_\_\_\_\_

Permanent Address - Yaktpur (Baroda), Tq: Ausa, Dist: Latur 413512 (MAHARASHTRA)

Date of Birth - 1st December 1983

Marrital Status - Married

Known Languages - Hindi, Marathi, English